Gerson Ramirez ← Download the most updated version following the link on the name.

Address

Fort Laurderdale, FL, 33311

Phone (s)

Cell: (under request)

Email antillgrp@gmail.com (preferred contact)

Linked in https://www.linkedin.com/in/bcs-gerson-ramirez

GitHub https://github.com/antillgrp









I am professional with more than ten years of experience in many different IT areas, such as software development, systems and networking.

!! Federal ACTIVE Department of Commerce (DoC) Moderate Background Investigation (MBI) Public Trust Clearance. To inquire further regarding verification of clearance, please contact Census Investigative Services (CIS).

## **Education and Certifications**

- MIT Cloud & DevOps: Continuous Transformation at Massachusetts Institute of Technology
- Master of Science in Software Development at Maryville University of St. Louis. (GPA: 4.0 (Gerson Unofficial Transcript 8 26 2020.pdf))
- **Bachelor's in Computer Science** (07/2009)

# Official Certifications:

**Majors** 

- Oracle Certified Professional: Java SE 11 Developer (Certification Number: 282095428OCPJSE11-J)
- Object Oriented Application Development in JAVA (Certification Number: R073015600232)
- **ReactJS with Redux Certification** (Certification Number: BT4Y8AVC)
- Cisco Certified Network Associate ( CCNA ) (Certificate Verification Number: Q58VEEDPF3RQQPG1)
- Microsoft Certified Azure Administrator Associate (Certification Number: H524-5526)
- Red Hat® Certified System Administrator (RHCSA) (Certification Number: In progress ...)
- NIIT Red Hat® Linux System Administration (Certification Number: 07HO-MMS-0123)
- NIIT TCP/IP and Red Hat® Linux Essentials (Certification Number: 07HO-MMS-0059)

# Certificates and Trainings:

- **Spring Boot and Microservices**
- **Docker & Kubernetes Workshop**
- CDW application development cross-training (6 weeks) (C#, ASP.NET Web API, SQL SERVER, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY)
- (Training) AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator
- (Training) Certificate CISCO CCNA Training (176 Hours)
- (Training 290 hours) Helpdesk Agent
- Microsoft WS 2008 Network Services Administration Course
- Microsoft WS 2008 Active Directory Administration Course

#### Software development skills and competences:

- Expertise in OOP and Functional languages like Java (Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA, etc.), NodeJS, Python, C#, TypeScript, ...
- Advanced knowledge in Backend Frontend integration with trends opensource libraries like ReactJS (JS, TS, Redux, React-Router, React-Bootstrap, React-Material-UI, etc.), Angular, VueJS. Knowledge of web services with solid understanding of the RESTful Architecture and SOAP. Knowledgeable in full stack development, platforms, frameworks and front-end libraries, Java frameworks, .Net Framework, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, Entity Framework, NodeJS (back-end libraries like express, sequelize and many others).
- Strong knowledge Object-Oriented Paradigm, SOLID adherence and GoF Design Patterns. Comprehensive experience with Databases design and administration and DB guery languages, such as MS SQL Server and MySQL. High proficiency using IDEs and debugging tools, Microsoft Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, NetBeans, etc.
- Accredited certifications for Docker & Kubernetes Workshop and Spring Boot and Microservices.
- (Cert) AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator and (Training) AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator

# Work experience

Occupation or position held

## Software Integration Engineer (01/2022 – current)

- Deploy and support (L2) Certscan, CIS
- Functions and main responsibilities
- Deploy, configure, automatize, scripting (bash, python, PowerShell, java, .net), desktop, server OS (Linux (Red Hat EL, Centos, Ubuntu Server, etc.), Windows Server(2008, 2012, 2016)), and virtualization platforms (VMWare ESXi (6.5, 7.0, Tanzu TKG), HyperV). Docker and Kubernetes.
- DevOps: Kubernetes(Tanzu, Kustomize, Air-Gapped, Harbor). Docker, Scripting(CI/CD), Virtualization, VMWare, Networking, Linux

Employer S2 Global, Apps Dept

References Sivaraj Pasumalaithevan Sr DevOps Eng. (siva@digitaloctant.com)

Occupation or position held **Specialist Programmer** (06/2021 – 01/2022) Full Stack Spring Microservices and ReactJS/Angular Functions and main Java (8/11) (Core, Spring, Microservices, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud (RestTemplate, Ribbon, Eureka, Hystrix, Zuul, Sleuth, Consul, etc.), responsibilities Hibernate, JPA, etc.) MSSql, MySQL, MongoDB Infosys Employer Occupation or position held IT Systems/Network/Hardware Technician level II Enterprise Area (06/2016 – 05/2021) Application development cross-training (6 weeks) (C#, ASP.NET Web API, SQL SERVER, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY) Functions and main Install, configure troubleshoot and upgrade Server/Racks hardware, software, networks (routers/switches/wireless) and peripheral equipment. responsibilities Deploy, configure, automatize, scripting (bash, python, PowerShell), desktop, server OS (Linux (Red Hat EL, Centos, Ubuntu Server, etc.), Windows Server(2008, 2012, 2016)), and virtualization platforms (VMWare ESXi (6.5, 7.0), HyperV) Employer CDW in configuration center. References Annual Performance Review 2020 Broadband Premises Installer (08/2015 to 06/2016) IES Residential, Inc. - Las Vegas, NV Occupation or position held Contact: Amaury Arencibia (Supervisor): +1-702-485-9266 Occupation or position held Computer Technician/Web Developer (01/01/2013 to 09/30/2014) - Web applications development CMS based, joomla, drupal, wordpress. - Systems Installation and Configuration, O.Systems Windows, Linux, MacOS, Unix (FreeBSD). - Installation and configuration of wired and wireless networks, and network equipment. Functions and main - Repairing and maintaining all sort of computer equipment. responsibilities - Remote Assistance and Customer Support. - Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboards, printers) Employer **Freelance** (customers references only) Occupation or position held IT Systems and Hardware Technician/Web Developer (03/01/2011 to 12/31/2012) - Small web applications development CMS based, Joomla, Drupal, Wordpress. Functions and main - Systems Installation and Configuration, O.Systems Windows, Linux, MacOS, Unix (FreeBSD). responsibilities - Installation and configuration of wired and and post-sales support. **Employer** Informática Profesional de Canarias. Occupation or position held System Technician and Final User Support (06/01/10 to 07/30/10) - Small web applications development CMS based, Joomla, Drupal, WordPress. - Member of the team in charge of the migration and deploying of "Drago" System (Unified and centralized system of health information), Canary Islands Functions and main Health Service. responsibilities - Also, giving technical onsite customer support. - Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboards, printers) Employer Arcitel Ibérica, S.A, Tenerife (Spain) Occupation or position held **Dependent Technical of Cybercafe (retailer IT shop)** (05/09 - 05/10) - Systems Installation and Configuration, O.Systems Windows. - Installation and configuration of wired and wireless networks, and network equipment. Functions and main - Repairing and maintaining all sort of computer equipment. responsibilities - Remote Assistance and Customer Support. - Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboards, printers) Employer Cybercafe Cybermar, Tenerife (Spain) Occupation or position held Network and Systems Administrator and Management Computing (04/2008 - 04/2009) - Internet enterprises services management (email, web, others) Functions and main - Administration and maintenance physical (cable, routers, switches) and logical network (active directory, users, group policy, security, responsibilities databases systems, others). - Analysis and implementation of projects (see Degree Project (Spanish)) **Employer** ICM (Instituto Cubano de la Música), Ministerio de Cultura., Havana (Cuba) Occupation or position held Network and Systems technician specialist (07/2007 to 03/2008) - Implementing, deploying and administration of mail, web and mailing list Unix servers (FreeBSD and Linux) in a dedicated Datacenter. Functions and main (see Degree Project (Spanish)) responsibilities - Networking maintenance. - Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboards, printers) Employer CUBARTE (Centro de Informática para la Cultura), Min. de Cultura, Habana (Cuba)